

Mahesh Pradeep Kulkarni

Contact Details: +919511794301 / +918055527213 | Pune | Email: mpk27213@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY- Work Experienced: 5 Years

I am an Experienced Business Analyst and result oriented professional with a demonstrated history of working in Manufacturing, Supply Chain Management, Mobility, FMCG and Pharma Domains. I focus on data visualization, interactive reporting, cleaning, and getting statistical insights from data. I enjoy building bespoke data tools. I also use data science to contribute on GitHub, StackOverflow. I am lucky to get to use R and RStudio tools on a daily basis to help others learn from genetic and molecular data and to communicate their results through dashboards and interactive reports. Currently, leading a team of 5 members working on sales compensation planning and implementation.

Strong Data Science professional with a PG in Data Analytics from IIIT – Bangalore.

Experience



Assistant Manager: Genpact, Pune (Domain- Pharma)

December 2021- Present

Working as Business Analyst for Leading Pharma Company in US, Where I Lead BI Projects, Building Forecasting Revenue Simulators using RShiny, Spotfire. Also manage projects on Octopoda cloud platform where we deploy the project.

- Covid- 19 Simulator- Build a Forcast Simulator using RShiny on Covid-19 Data which will Forecast the How many Number of
 Patients Will be infect in Next 10 Years. Also forecast Mild, Moderate range of Patients and the How much revenue will
 generate in next 10 Years from Covid-19 Medicines.
- Chronic Cough Simulator Revenue Model- Build a Chronic Cough simulator for United States and Germany Factory using R and Spotfire. In this the simulator will visualize the forecasting Data for different different products. The Simulator forecast the sales for next 11 years on basis of Patients data.
- Spesolimab Data Management- Many Pharmacies from USA provides patient data and In this I am performing Data cleaning operations. I get data on daily basis and weekly basis. I need to check null records as per Pharmacies agreement and share reports on weekly and monthly with client.
 Tools- Rstudio Pro, Rstudio Connect and Octopoda

-

Business Analyst: Collabera Technologies, Pune (Domain- Pharma)

May 2021- Nov 2021

Handling an IC project for a US pharma client worth more than \$1M which includes 700 field reps with a total yearly payout close to \$25M. Key responsibilities includes:

- **Project Delivery:** End to end reporting of IC as per the pre-defined timelines. Collaborate with different teams to ensure the processes are integrated together and the quality is maintained. Primary roles in IC ops includes: End to End IC reporting in Contest; sales crediting for 4 brands in different territories
 - IC Assessment & Design on a yearly basis
 - MBO Design to drive the required field behavior
 - Process Improvement to increase efficiency by at least 5% per year
 - Tools used to create Report- R Markdown, Excel, PowerBI
- Contest Report- Analysis of Products sales on the basis of Weekly, Monthly time frame
- Rexulti Dashboard- The purpose of this dashboard is to provide factory level views into planned & actual calls, sample promotional programs execution i.e. a high level picture of brand coverage.
 - Tools used to create Dashboard- R Shiny, R Programming, PowerBI
- Team & Task Management: Handling the team of 5 associates working in sales crediting and IC admin verticals and keeping the quality and timelines of the project intact
- Client engagement at a weekly level to understand their requirements and accordingly suggest the best options to meet their needs. Coordinating with the clients to level set expectations/ scope in case of any ad-hoc work
- Mentorship: Collaborating with the young members to understand their aspirations and help them work towards achieving the goals set. As a mentor, I understand the grievances of the juniors in the team and address them with the help of the senior leadership
- Creating SOW for ad-hoc processes requested by the clients
- Ad-hoc budget tracker: Track the ad-hoc budget worth \$200K and help clients decide the best areas to utilize the budget which would help in overall growth and efficiency

Data Analyst: Cyient Ltd, Pune (1 Year 6 Months) (Domain- Manufacturing and Supply Chain Management)

- Find Insights for the Paint Shops of US Based Manufacturers. Managed and built all the Data Products (administrative part)
 on Rstudio Teams. For Creating Data Products R Shiny, R Markdown tools are used.
- Create a Data pipeline- Databricks, Rstudio Connect, Rstudio Package manager
 - Collect Huge amount of Data and store it in DBFS. The Data is related to the Paint shops.
 where tractors parts are painted. Creating a cluster which manages this Data and Perform ETL operations
 on this data using Databricks Notebook in R and SQL. Automate this Jobs in Databricks Platform.
 Then getting this Data in RStudio for further Data Analytics.
 Manage Shiny apps on Rstudio Connect, Manage libraries in Rstudio Package Manager
 - Manage Shirly apps on Astudio Connect, Manage ilbraries in Astudio Fackage Manag
- Enterprise Paint Performance System R Shiny, Keras, R Plotly, Highcharter, Rstudio Team
 - Create a Shiny App for improving Safety, Productivity and Quality of Vehicles in Paint System.

 Using this application, they make changes in their process for getting perfect results, they can save lots of paint and also save a huge cost in millions of Dollars.
- Manufacturing SPC Dashboard for Harvester System- RShiny, Plotly, Highcharter
 - o Create a shiny App which contains an SPC Dashboard with many Insights.
 - o Capture data from pdf and convert into Table like structure format.
 - o Perform Data Visualization using High Performance Libraries like Plotly, Highcharter

EC Mobility and Expert Global Solutions, Aurangabad (2 Years 3 Months)

Work as a Programmer Analyst and Data Engineer for EC Mobility and Expert Global Solutions. Expert Global is a Parent Organization of EC Mobility. I work for Expert Global Solutions from EC Mobility and after one year I internally shifted to Expert Global Solutions. Here, I worked for FMCG and Mobility Domain. I delivered bespoke Data Products to the fortune 500 listed groups.

 Programmer Analyst: Expert Global Solutions (Domain- FMCG) Aug 2018- Jul 2019

- o Make Reports of OEE, Downtime Analysis using Tableau Desktop
- o Build a rest-full API for R and Angular Integration.
- o Real time Statistical Process Control Model Dashboard
- o Real time Correlation Dashboard using- R Shiny, R Plotly
- Data Engineer: EC Mobility (Domain- Mobility)

May 2017- July 2018

Working on Driverless Car Project for German Based leading Car Manufacturer. Collects thousands of Object Labelled Images annotating. Find the Insights from the labelled data. Create the Reports for Quality of Labelled Images

- o Developed the reports using RMarkdown and Tableau Desktop
- o Track -Pro Data analysis and Visualization

 Track Pro is a web App which includes the track report of employees. In this I perform **EDA**, Data Visualization
- Contribute to Open Source Projects Over GitHub Such and Stack Overflow

R Shiny, ShinyDashboardPlus, bs4dash, Plotly, shiny Mobile, plumber....

Development of R Package Corrly, contains All Types of Correlation Charts

Academic Credentials

PG Diploma in Data Analytics, IIIT-Bangalore & UpGrad | CGPA 2.7 / 4

Apr 2017- Mar 2018

• BE (Computer Science) | Percentage: 64

Jawaharlal Nehru Engineering College | BAMU, Aurangabad (Maharashtra)

2017

• Polytechnic (Computer Science) | MSBTE | Percentage: 66.26

2014

Key Skills

Tools- RStudio, Rstudio Teams, Rstudio Connect, Tableau, PowerBI, RStudio Connect, Databricks, R Shiny

R Packages- dplyr. Tidiverse, shiny, sparklyr, Rmarkdown, ggplot, highcharter, Plotly

Certifications: Professional Databricks Certified

Accolades

LinkedIn ID- https://www.linkedin.com/in/themaheshkulkarni/